以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，所以我想我今天就开始了
ok so I thought I'd begin today with as
我们要来排序的结束
we're coming to the end of the sort of
专注于线性代数和移动到
focus on linear algebra and moving on to
一点点概率
a little probability a a little more
优化和很多深刻的
optimization and a a lot of deep
系统的学习，这是像我的方式
learning so this was like my way of
回顾写下大事
review to write down the big
矩阵的因式分解等我的
factorizations of a matrix and so my
想法，它有点喜欢它
idea and it's kind of enjoyed it as
检查一些免费的
checking that a number of free
参数在L＆U或q和r或中表示
parameters say in L&U or in q and r or
每个人的每一个人数
every each of those that the number of
自由参数与数字一致
free parameters agrees with the number
其中的参数如N平方
of parameters in a itself like N squared
通常所以通常有N平方和
usually so a usually has N squared and
然后我们可以在我们之后更换一个if
then can we replace a if after we've
计算你可以扔掉一个是的
computed Ln you can we throw away a yes
因为所有信息都在L和
because all the information is in L and
U和它用n矩阵填充相同的n
U and it fills that same n by n matrix
这很明显，因为L是
well that's kind of obvious because L is
下三角形和对角线全部
a lower triangular and the diagonal all
那些没有不自由参数
ones is not are not free parameters and
U是三角形的上三角形和
U is triangular upper triangular and
这是自由的枢轴
it's diagonal the pivots those are free
这样的参数，但我可以写
parameters so that but can I just write
倒数，所以我会经历
down the count so so I'll go through
我这之后很快就完成了这些
each of these just quickly after I've
弄清楚这些是怎样的
figured out how these are the sort of
这个积木有多少免费
the building blocks so how many free
这两个参数都在那里
parameters are there in these two
我觉得三角矩阵很好
triangular matrices well I think the
回答
answer
1/2和n减1和1/2以及n加1
1/2 and n minus 1 and 1/2 and n plus 1
这是一个熟悉的数字，是一些
that's a familiar number that's the some
你认识到这是1的总和
of you recognize that as the sum of 1
加2到n，你有一个免费/
plus 2 up to n and you have one free /
在上三角你
in the in the upper triangular you
你有一个免费参数
you've got one free parameter up in the
在下一个角落2和你一样
corner 2 in the next one and as you're
下来你最终得到了n
coming down you end up with n on the
主对角线，他们加起来
main diagonal and they add up to that
而且你看到那两个是不同的
and you see that those two are different
由n这是我们想要的好
by n which is what we want okay
对比答案明显如何
diagonal the answers obviously in how
关于特征向量矩阵，所以这是
about the eigenvector matrix so this is
这整个练习就像是一件事
this whole exercise is like something
我从来没有在教科书中看过
I've never seen in a textbook in and
它只是但对我来说带回所有
it's just but for me it brings back all
这些关键真的是浓缩的过程
these key really the condensed course in
线性代数是在该顶线，使得
linear algebra is on that top line so
一个多少个免费参数
how many free parameters in an
特征向量矩阵当然可以
eigenvector matrix okay and of course
你是在想什么是规则
you're sort of thinking what's the rule
对于免费参数所以我的答案是
for free parameters so the my answer is
将是免费的数量
going to be for the number of free
参数，所以这是一个N乘n矩阵
parameters so this is an N by n matrix
其中有n个特征向量但是
with the n eigenvectors in it but
那里有一定的自由和什么
there's a certain freedom there and what
是我们拥有的自由
is that what freedom do we have in
每个选择特征向量矩阵
choosing the eigenvector matrix every
特征向量可以乘以a
eigen vector can be multiplied by a
标量如果x是特征向量，则为2x
scalar if x is an eigenvector so is 2x
所以是3倍，所以我们可以做到
so is 3x so we could we could make a
会议第一部分是
convention that the first component was
总是1也许不会是最多的
always 1 maybe that wouldn't be the most
世界上的智能会议但是
intelligent convention in the world but
它会显示那一行的顶行
it would show that that top row of ones
不算数，所以我得到N.
were not to be counted so I get N
平方减去那个哦，好吧
squared minus n for that oh yeah well
做了那些
having done those
-让我让我看看这个
- let me let me look at this at this one
不说出来，总那么平方
does that come out a total then squared
是的，因为特征向量x有N.
yes because the eigenvector x has N
平方减去N乘这个推理小
squared minus n by this reasoning little
hokey推理我刚才给的和
hokey reasoning that I just gave and
然后还有更多的特征值
then there n more for the eigenvalue
矩阵，没有什么可留给的
matrix and there's nothing left for the
因为它是本征的逆
eigen the inverse because it's
由x确定所以你看到计数
determined by x so do you see the count
现在我加起来为n平方
adding up to n squared for those now I
开着正交一个我觉得我们
left open the orthogonal one I think we
那种在谈论期间谈到的那种
kind of talked about that during the
当我们遇到它时，它会少一些
when we met it and it's a little less
显而易见，但你还记得我是吗？
obvious but do you remember so I'm
谈论N乘n正交
talking about an N by n orthogonal
矩阵Q所以有多少自由参数
matrix Q so how many free parameters in
第一列，那列是我们的
column one that that column is what we
总是打电话给Q1它是否有免费结束
always call Q 1 does it have end free
参数或是否有条件
parameters or is there a condition that
削减那些有一个条件
that cuts that back there is a condition
对，什么是条件
right and what's the condition on the
删除一个的第一列
first column that that removes one
参数它的标准化它的长度是
parameter it's normalized it's length is
1所以我只从第一个得到n减1
1 so I only get n minus 1 from the first
专栏，现在如果我转移到
column and now if I move over to the
第二列有多少免费参数
second column how many free parameters
再一次，这是一个单位矢量，但也
there again it's a unit vector but also
它与第一个正交到两个正交
it is orthogonal to the first so to two
参数得到了两个强加的规则
parameters got you two rules got imposed
和两个参数得到去除，这
and two parameters got removed so this
是n减2然后最后是什么
is n minus 2 and then finally whatever
所以我认为那些家伙
so I think that that some of these guys
和我们在这里完全一样
is exactly the same that we had up here
我认为它也是1/2和n减1或
I think it's also 1/2 and n minus 1 or
1/2平方-亚当是的，所以不是
1/2 n squared - Adam yeah yeah so not as
你可能认为很多就像矩阵一样
many as you might think as the matrix is
大小N平方现在可以使用那些
size N squared now can I use those
因为这些就像建筑物一样
because these are the like the building
块我可以看看这些让我们看看
blocks can I just check these let's see
沿着清单L次你这么L
just go along the list L times u so L
有这个，你有，当我添加
had this and you had that and when I add
那些它加起来N平方正确的
those it adds up to N squared right the
减去取消加号和半个N.
minus cancels the plus and the half N
平方两次给我N平方那么好
squared twice gives me N squared so good
那个
for that one
那么QR井R是上层
what about Q R well R is upper
三角形如此然后Q哦是的我们
triangular like so and then Q oh yeah we
只是在那里得到它所以Q次R
just got it right there so for Q times R
这就是Plus再次加入N.
it's that Plus that again adding to N
对那个平方很好并且平方
squared good for that one and squared
对于一个这一次，我们只是做了ñ
for that one this one we just did N
平方减去N和X并且在
squared minus N and X and on the
对角线总N平方怎么样
diagonal total N squared what about this
关于人的大O真正
guy what about the Big O really
我通常会这样做的基本原则
fundamental one that I would normally
将矩阵写为s而不是a
write the matrix as s instead of a to
提醒我们，这里的矩阵
remind us that it that the matrix here
是对称的，所以我不期待看到
is symmetric so I'm not expecting ensk
我应该拥有对称的地方
where'd for a symmetric me I should have
把它放在我的名单上
put that on my list
对称矩阵的计数是多少
what's the count for a symmetric matrix
在这里，所以我不期待得到N.
s here so I'm not expecting to get N
平方我只是期待得到
squared I'm only expecting to get the
对称的数量是多少
number of symmetric s what's the number
自由参数，我会是我
of free parameters that I would that I
从那开始我希望会重新出现
start with that I hope will reappear in
Q和lambda有多少是什么交易
Q and lambda so how many what's the deal
对于一个对称矩阵让我们看看我
for a symmetric matrix let's see I'm
自由选择是相同的计数为
free to choose is it the same count as
这是的，因为我可以自由地选择
this yeah because I'm free to choose the
上三角部分和对角线
upper triangular part and the diagonal
但我不能自由选择较低的
but I'm not free to choose the lower so
所以我说它是n=1的1/2n倍
so I'd say it's 1/2 n times n minus 1
并且加上在那里确定，所以对不起对角线
and plus sorry diagonals in there ok so
我明白了吗
do I get that
这些家伙的N平方加一半加n
half of N squared plus n from these guys
好吧，我可能做对角线的人
well I probably do the diagonal guy
让我在这给了我，那是一个
gives me in this gives me n and that's a
Q这是我最喜欢的号码
Q which is my other favorite number
在那里，当我把它添加到那个
there and when I add that to that that
变成一个加号，我好耶
becomes a plus sign and I'm good yeah
你知道我喜欢这样做但是
you see how I enjoy doing this right but
我快要结束了，但是最后一个
I'm near the end but the last one it's
有点不太知名好的Q时间说
kind of not well known okay Q time says
你还记得那个因素分解
do you remember that factorization
这就是所谓的极性分解
that's a called the polar decomposition
这是一个正交时间a
it's a it's an orthogonal times a
对称的，经常用于
symmetric and it is often used in
工程作为一种分解方法
engineering as a way to decompose a
无论如何，位移或应变矩阵Q.
displacement or strain matrix anyway Q
倍于此，它实际上是非常的
times this and it actually it is very
非常接近SVD，我有朋友
very close to the SVD and I have friends
谁更好地计算Qs而不是
who say better to compute Q s than the
SVD然后只是继续前进Q.
SVD and then just move along anyway Q
这个时候Q就是这个人，而且是什么
times this so Q is this guy and s what's
对称的是这个家伙
s symmetric that's this guy
所以，Q让我写那封信Q.
so that's Q let me write that letter Q
所以我不会失去它
and s so I don't lose it
那些是什么加起来和平方
what are those add up to and squared
快乐好，所以最后SVD友好了
happy ok so finally the SVD friendly the
SVD是什么计数
SVD what's the count
好吧现在我不知道我有
well now I don't know I've got
那里有长方形的东西，所以我有
rectangular stuff in there so I've got
我准备好了这个，我必须这样做
to I'm ready for this one and I have to
觉得有点
think a little bit
我们可能已经这样做了所以我拥有了
and we may have done this so I have I
让我们假设M等于M
let's suppose that M is lesser equal M
假设它是，否则我们
suppose that it is yeah otherwise we
只会转置并查看SVD
would just transpose and look at the SVD
所以让我们说M小于或等于n所以让我们来吧
so let's say M less or equal n so let's
说它有完整的排名，是什么
say it's got full rank and what's the
矩阵可以具有M的最大等级
largest rank that the matrix can have M
显然满级M所以SVD将是M.
clearly full rank M so the SVD will be M
由M让我们记住你的
by M let's remember the the you the
Sigma和V转置这将是M
Sigma and the V transpose this will be M
通过n，这将是n乘以n
by n and this will be n by n for the
满刻度这个VD，如果排名是
full scale this VD and if the rank is
等于M然后我真的希望得到我
equal to M then I really expect to get I
期望它加起来总和
expect it to add up to the total for a
对于原始的a有MN的权利
for a the original a has MN right it's
在M×n矩阵中，矩阵a是M乘以n
an M by n matrix the matrix a is M by n
与他们在给予我的方面较少或相等
with them less or equal in giving me
这些东西也有MN参数这样做
these things so has MN parameters so do
我们得到M倍n在此，我希望我们做的
we get M times n from this I hope we do
我知道我们从Sigma获得了多少
I know how many we get from Sigma what
什么是SigmaM的数量
how many what's the count for a Sigma M
什么是V的计数，所以这是一个
and what's the count for V so that's an
Nbyn，你的数量还算什么呢
N by n and what's the count for you okay
是的，他们是正交矩阵，所以
yeah they're orthogonal matrices so that
我应该能够达到那条路线
I should be able to go up to that line
这是MbyMone，所以就是这样
this was an M by M one so that's is that
一半和一个减去我复制那个
a half and n minus one am i copying that
正确了这个圈子的存在
correctly out of this circle there
那就是M乘M正交
that's that's an M by M orthogonal
矩阵哦
matrix Oh
但我必须写出来，这是愚蠢的
but I have to write in that was foolish
好吧，他们是啊因为那个矩阵
okay em em yeah because that matrix
这是一个大小M，所以这是一个M然后我
it's a size M so that's an M and then I
有那个，然后我有任何V
have that and then I have whatever V
转移结束n哦什么是交易
transpose end by n oh what's the deal in
嗯
there hmm
我想要所有1/2+n减1哦
do I want all of the 1/2 + n minus 1 Oh
上帝，我以为我会直截了当
God I thought I'd got this straight
他知道我的意思是我可以减去
does he know I meant I could subtract
从这个，并找出我
this from this and and find out what I
应该说哇
should say whoa
众所周知，学生也会这样做
students have been known to do this too
让我们看看好吧，无论如何都要试着去思考
let's see well let's try to think anyway
所以我有这个n由n提交n
so I have this n by n submit this n by n
正交矩阵，所以它是第一个它
orthogonal matrix so it's first it could
它可以是任何正交矩阵是的
it could be any orthogonal matrix yeah
但它只是前M列
but is it only the first M columns that
我真的需要休息，我可以
I really need the rest I could just
扔掉所以我让我试着想象
throw away so I let me try to imagine
它只是我的第一口井
that it's just the first well then I
在这里不会有任何结局，所以也许我
won't have any end in here so maybe I
最好拿1/2，你知道帮助哦哦
better take 1/2 and you know help oh oh
当然是
yes of course
哈，我只有M列才重要
ha I've got only M columns that matter
现在每个人都喜欢的诱饵
the bait the everybody sort of now
了解SVD我们是对的
understands that SVD we've got the right
等级是我不要忘了那么好
the rank is am don't forget that ok then
第一个是第一个M
the first the the first are the first M
的V列是很重要的是
columns of V are important those are the
非零的奇异向量
singular vectors that go with nonzero
真正重要的奇异值
singular values that really matter so
那是什么，其余的并不重要
that's and the rest really don't matter
所以
so
所以我只想知道如何
so I'm going to just I have to count how
很多，所以抱歉V重要
many so here sorry V the the important
你的一部分有多少只有M
part of thee has has how many and only M
列，但它是一个N乘n矩阵和
columns but it's an N by n matrix and
那些列是正交的，所以很荣幸
those columns are orthogonal so honor
答案是不MN这家伙的我
the answer is not MN for this guy its I
必须经历这种愚蠢
have to go through this foolish
再次推理我有n减1加n
reasoning again I have n minus 1 plus n
减2加上等加n减M
minus 2 plus so on plus n minus M there
在第一个中是n减1个参数
were n minus 1 parameters in the first
在思想哦矢量或单位矢量
over thought oh vector or a unit vector
n减去2，在第二个到n
n minus 2 in the second one up to n
在第三个减去M然后V有一些
minus M in the third and then V has some
更多真正来自的专栏
more columns that are coming really from
这是不是一个空的空间都没有
a null space that that are not are not
重要
important
我相信这是正确的做法
I believe this is the right thing to do
我希望你同意，现在我的意思
I'm hoping you agree and now I I mean
我希望那些更多的东西
I'm hoping even more that those that up
好几次，我有一半和
to M times in okay I have a half and
广场他们必须完成这件事
square they have to total this thing
好吧，这有mm条款
okay this had m m terms
所以有这些目的，然后我
so there's m m of these ends and then I
必须减去一加二加
have to subtract off one plus two plus
三个到M，所以我是什么
three up to M and so what am i
减去一些人的东西
subtracting off what's that some one
加上两个加三个停在M的位置
plus two plus three stopping at M it's
其中一个半人是1/2毫米
one of these guys one-half is it 1/2 mm
再加上一个1/2米米加1个对不起1/2米
plus one yeah 1/2 m m plus 1 sorry 1/2 m
m加1我应该喜欢这个
m plus 1 I would supposed to enjoy this
而且现在有点紧张但是没关系，所以我
and now little nervous but okay so I
相信那
believe that that
是的，我们有明确的MN
is that okay well we have the MN that's
这是一个很好的迹象，我们正在拍摄
a good sign that we're shooting for so
它的其余部分是否会增加
does the rest of it add to nothing well
我猜是的，我猜我放的时候会这样
I guess yeah I guess it does when I put
这两个在一起我有1/2毫米加
these two together I have 1/2 mm plus
一个然后我将它减去
one and then I'm subtracting it away
再来，所以我得到了阿门
again so I get amen
好吧，我们什么都不会
all right well we wouldn't anything
在我举起董事会并委托之前
before I raise that board and consign
对历史来说，我应该停下来
that to history is there should I pause
多一点分钟，这将是像
a little more minute this will be like
我希望有一页的附录
I'm hoping a one-page appendix to the
笔记和书，你会看到它但是
notes and the book and you'll see it but
我有一个多计数做，然后
I do have one more count to do and then
我对这篇评论很满意并准备好了
I'm good with this review and ready to
继续前进到马鞍的话题
move onward to the topic of saddle
积分并准备继续前进
points and ready to move onward after
那好，我会说大约一点点
that well I'll say a little bit about
我正在创建的下一个实验作业
the next lab homework that I'm creating
然后我们的下一个主题将是
and then our next topic will be like
协方差矩阵有点
covariance matrices it a little
本周统计我们和我们
statistics this week and then we and we
得到一个星期的假，我们能来消化它，
get a week off we could to digest it and
然后回来进行梯度下降和
then come back for gradient descent and
深度学习和那些事情还可以
deep learning and and those things okay
每个人都对此很满意，那么我的是什么
everybody happy with that so what's my
最后一个问题我的最后一个问题是
final question my final question is the
SVD用于任何秩R的任何矩阵，从而
SVD for for any any matrix of rank R so
它是一个M乘n矩阵，但等级是
it's an M by n matrix but the rank is
只有R.
only R
这是一个自然的问题多少
it's a natural question how many
参数存在于排名为R的a中
parameters are there in a in a ranked R
矩阵，这可能是我们甚至可能有
matrix and that may be we may even have
谈到这个问题，我有两个
touched on this question and I have two
回答它的方法和一种方法是SVD
ways to answer it and one way is the SVD
所以，让我和那个类似于什么
so let me and that'll be similar to what
如果排名是，我只是推到那里
I just pushed up there so if the rank is
我们这个典型排名的SVD我们的
our the SVD of this typical rank our
矩阵将是你的西格玛V转置，但
matrix will be u Sigma V transpose but
你知道这就像凝聚了一样
you know this is the like the condensed
我扔掉东西的东西
thing where I've thrown away stuff
这是自动为零，因为如果
that's automatically zero because if the
排名只是我们喜欢的排名
rank is only our like if the rank was
一个人认为排名不是我那个人
one suppose the rank wasn't one then I'd
有一列时间一个西格玛时间
have one column times one sigma times
一排，我可以做到这一点
one row right and I could do that count
对于R等于1我现在有了我们的专栏
for R equal one now I have our columns
所以这是M是否有西格玛是它的
so this is M by are there Sigma is its
对角线当然所以我会得到我们的
diagonal of course so I'm gonna get our
数字，而现在这个数字
numbers out of that and this one is now
换句话说R也许我应该
R by n in other words maybe I should
像在这里保存这一点，这是
like save this little bit here that was
有帮助
helpful
但现在我已经将M减少到R所以我
but now I've got M is reduced to R so I
相信如果算上这三个我就会
believe that if I count these three I'll
为a获取正确数量的参数
get the right number of parameters for a
排名R矩阵，这不是那么明显
rank R matrix and that's not so obvious
因为等级R矩阵不是我们的
because the rank R matrices are not a we
如果我有一个等级R，则没有子空间
don't have a subspace if I had a rank R
矩阵到另一个秩R矩阵
matrix to another rank R matrix
这个等级可能大到2r和
well the rank could be as big as 2r and
可能会这样，所以我们你知道它
probably will be so so we you know it's
得到你的一点点有趣
just a little interesting to get your
交给R级矩阵因为
hands on matrices of rank R because
他们有点像数学的罪
they're kind of a sin like a well math
人会称之为歧管一些
person would call it a manifold some
一种表面
kind of a surface
在矩阵空间中，你有没有
in matrix space yeah have you ever
考虑矩阵空间，这是一个
thought about matrix space so that's a
向量空间，因为我们可以添加矩阵
vector space because we can add matrices
我们可以将它们乘以常数
we can multiply them by constants we can
采取NIR组合所以他们是
take the NIR combination so they're
如果我们，我们可以称它们为向量
there we could call them vectors if we
这样就是M的向量空间
like that would be a vector space of M
通过n矩阵将是什么
by n matrices what would be the
那个空间支撑的尺寸所以
dimension of that space support so the
矢量空间的所有三个四
vector space of all three by four
具有什么维度的矩阵
matrices that that has what dimension
1212因为你有12个号码
1212 because you've got 12 numbers to
选择它，因为你是一个空间
choose and it is a space because you're
如果我说3乘4矩阵，现在就加
gonna add now if I say 3 by 4 matrices
等级2我再也没有空间了
of Rank 2 I don't have a space anymore
那个词空间就是睡着了
that word spaces is is priscilly asleep
保留用于意义向量空间
reserved for meaning vector space
意思是我可以采取组合，但如果我
meaning I can take combinations but if I
取2级矩阵加2级
take a rank 2 matrix plus a rank 2
矩阵我不是那么它是一种表面
matrix I'm not so it's sort of a surface
在12D到3x4矩阵内
within 12 D the to the 3 by 4 matrices
等级2的和我们即将找到
of Rank 2 and we're about to find the
那个表面的尺寸会影响你的想法
dimension of that surface does your mind
在12中可视化表面
sort of visualize the surface in 12
尺寸是的，好好试一试
dimensions yeah well give it a shot
无论如何，但那表面可以
anyway and but what that surface could
有11维可以这么说
have the 11 dimensional so to speak like
在本地意味着它不必
meaning locally the it wouldn't have to
是一个计划的11维飞机
be a plan 11 dimensional plane going
通过其实起源它不会
through the origin in fact it wouldn't
经过由来是因为产地
go through the origin because the origin
没有排名是如此，所以它是某种
won't have rank are so so it's some kind
一个表面，也许它有一些
of a surface and maybe it's got some
不同的部分可能有些聪明
different pieces probably some smart
人知道那个表面看起来像什么
person knows what that surface looks
等，但是我们只是要找出
like but we're just going to find out
有些人对它的数量有所了解
some sense something about its number of
参数作为局部维度我
parameters as local dimension well I
知道这个答案是我所得到的
know that this answer is R cuz I've got
我们的Sigma和这个我非常好
our Sigma's and this one I'm pretty good
但现在却不是
at but now it's not
它是Rbyn所以它不是在这里
it's R by n so it's instead of here here
我们是M但现在在这里R是R所以我
our was M but now down here R is R so I
认为它是n减1/2
think it's are n minus 1/2
什么是M所以现在它是一个
what's that is that an M so now it's an
RR加1我想我想和什么
R R plus 1 I think I think and what
关于你，所以U将会是相似的
about the u so U is going to be similar
除了在这里，我们已经到了
except instead of the end here we've got
一个MI所以我想我们会为你做的
an M I so I think we for you will will
有M减1加M减2加等等
have M minus 1 plus M minus 2 plus so so
让我在这里写下M减去1所以你
let me write it here M minus 1 so you
我在这里谈论你，这是我们的
I'm talking about you here it's got our
列第一个有M减1
columns the first one has M minus 1
因为我扔了一个，因为它是一个
because I throw away one because it's a
单位向量最多M减去R我们的列
unit vector up to M minus R ours column
好的，现在怎么样那是什么
okay and now so how what what is that
加起来我把所有的M都放好了
add up to well I put all the M's
因此，我们的M让我说先生
together so that's our M let me say mr
然后我中减去1加2
and then I'm subtracting off 1 plus 2
加3到R现在再告诉我什么
Plus 3 up to R now tell me again what
这加起来一加二加三
that adds up to one plus two plus three
停在我们这就是我们在这里所拥有的
stop at our that's what we had here and
我们已经把它用于V而且我们已经得到了它
we've got it for V and we've got it
再来这里减去1/2我们的R加1你
again here minus 1/2 our R plus 1 you
处之泰然
okay with that
现在我只是想把它们加起来所以我
and now I just want to add them up so I
有MR和我已经R然后我有
have M R and I've n R and then I have
其中两个让我让我得到它
two of these so let me let me get it
MR和n现在我必须这样做
here M R and n are and now I have to
看看如此先检查我现在检查了
look at so mr check n are checked now I
有两个这样的家伙，所以他们结合起来
have two of these guys so they combine
进入R平方加R然后IR
into R squared plus R and then I R
平方
squared
是的，减去R平方
yeah minus R squared
抱歉，他们合并为负R平方
sorry they combined into minus R squared
加上R然后这里有一个进来
plus R and then here's a are coming in
加上我认为我们有一个减去R
with a plus I think we have a minus R
平方，这是正确的答案
squared and that is the right answer
是的好了，所以我花了一点时间比我
yep okay so I took a bit longer than I
意，但它这是一个数字，
intended but it this is a number that
这很有趣
that's sort of interesting
我提到马鞍点有点像
I mentioned saddle points sort of like
分开最大值和最小值只
separately from maxima and minima just
因为它们绝对不那么容易
because they are definitely not as easy
和你一起工作明白我的意思
to work with you understand what I mean
通过涉及马鞍点矩阵
by saddle points matrices involved have
这些都不会肯定
are not positive definite those would go
最大限度，他们不是负面的
with a maximum they're not negative
他们不是消极的，他们并不好
they're not negative they're not well
那些将与最大值和最小值
those would go with maxima and minima
但我们是我们之间，在寻找
but we're we're looking in between so
马鞍点好吧我会开始的
saddle points okay well I'll get going
对那些没关系，我有点意识到这一点
on those okay I I sort of realized that
马鞍有两个主要来源
there are two main sources of saddle
他们中的一个点是当我有
points one of them is when I have
当我说我的时候出现的问题
problems that when I let's say I
最小化，这将是约束
minimize so this will be the constraint
马鞍点来自于
saddle points have come from the
约束让勒布朗拉格朗日会如此
constraint so LeBron Lagrange's gonna be
对这些马鞍点负责
responsible for these saddle points so
我们可能有像一些极小问题
we might have some minimum problem like
尽量减少一些肯定的事情
minimize some positive definite thing
当然，如果我们不再说了
and of course if we don't say anymore
最小值是零正确的，因为
the minimum is zero right because
否则它是积极的，但我们要走了
otherwise it's positive but we're going
把约束斧等于B所以这个
to put on constraints ax equal B so this
是经典的约束
is the classical constrained
优化问题二次成本
optimization problem quadratic cost
函数线性约束我们可以
function linear constraints we could
完全解决这个问题，但让我们看看
solve this exactly but let's just see
马鞍点会上升的地方
where saddle point is going to rise so
所以有
so there's
是肯定的，但现在我们如何
is positive-definite but now how do we
妥善处理这个问题
deal with that problem well the ground
说做什么Lagaan说看看
said what to do Lagaan said look at the
拉格朗日好吧，他介绍了lambda
Lagrangian okay he introduced lambda so
这个X在这个X中是n维
this X is in this X is in n dimensions
这是一个N乘n矩阵，但我有M.
that's an N by n matrix but I have M
约束因此矩阵a是M乘以n
constraints so the matrix a is M by n
我有M个约束然后我要去
I've M constraints and then I'm going to
按照规则介绍Mlagron
follow the rules and introduce M lagron
小应用者
smalt appliers
这是一个M，然后是整洁的部分
that's an M and then the neat part of
呻吟，什么是这个好
the groan and what what is this well
这是我参加的功能，然后我
it's I take the function and then I
介绍记住lambda是一个向量
introduce remember lambda is a vector
现在不只是一个数字
now not just a number
我们有一些应用，其中它是
we had some application where it was
只是，有一只约束，但是
just there was just one constraint but
现在我有M个约束，所以我拿了一个
now I have M constraints so I take a
lambdasolambdatransposetimesax
lambda so lambda transpose times ax
减去B和加号或减号
minus B and the plus or the minus sign
这里并不重要我的意思是你可以
here is not important I mean you can
选择它，因为那将决定
choose it because that'll determine the
lambda的标志，但不管怎样
sign of lambda but either way it's
正确
correct
好的，所以我们已经进入了它
okay so we've entered it we've
介绍了一个现在依赖的功能
introduced a function that now depends
X和还对Lambda和和有
on X and also on lambda and and there's
a和他们互相繁衍和我的
a and they multiply each other in and my
重点是拉格龙说的
point is that lagron says take the
关于X和λ的衍生物
derivatives with respect to X and lambda
所以这是他很酷的事情
so that's the cool thing that he's
他说，如果你只是创造
contributed he says if you only create
我的功能现在你可以拿X.
my function now you can take X
衍生物和λ衍生物
derivative and lambda derivative that
会给你n个X的方程式
will give you n equations for the X's
从这一个来自X衍生物和
from this one from the X derivative and
M方程从lambda到
M equations from the lambda to
它将是n加M它将决定
it'll be n plus M it'll determine the
好的X和lambda但是我说的
good X and the lambda but I'm saying it
这一切都是真的，但都很重要
that's all true and all important but
我是说X和那对X.
I'm saying that the X and that pair X
lambda将成为这个问题的一个重点
lambda will be a saddle point of this
功能此功能有鞍点
function this function has saddle points
不是没有最大的好
not not a maximum okay
让我们看看衍生品吧
let's just take the derivatives and see
我们得到这样与衍生品
what we get so the derivatives with
通过DX尊重XD我现在是一个
respect to X D by DX I'm ex is now a
矢量所以我真的应该说
vector so I really should say the
我得到了X方向的渐变
gradient in the X direction I get I get
SX和这里是规范的衍生物
SX and here the derivative of the spec
2x这就是转置
2x what that's that is a transpose
lambda因为这是点积
lambda because this is the dot product
一个转置lambda与X你，你
of a transpose lambda with X you you
我知道我已经把括号括起来了
know I've put parentheses around it and
遵循转置规则，这样
followed the transpose rule so that's
转置lambda的点积
the dot product of a transpose lambda
使用X，它在X中是线性的，所以它是
with X it's linear in X so it's
衍生物只是一个转置lambda
derivative is just a transpose lambda
那就是现在我拿另一个
and that's and now I take the other one
lambda衍生物lambda
the the lambda derivative the lambda
衍生物这不依赖于lambda
derivative this doesn't depend on lambda
lambda导数只是X减去
the lambda derivative is just a X minus
B它带来了约束
B it brings back the constraints so
这很简单，不，甚至没有
that's pretty simple no it doesn't even
需要很多思考，因为你只是
require much thought because you just
知道约束回来，
know the constraints are coming back and
当然应该把B放在这上面
of course B should be put over on this
因为它是一个常数所以我们
side because it's a constant so there we
看到一个块我们看到一个非常重要的
see to a block we see a important very
重要的一类问题和问题
important class of problems and the
矩阵我们看到我们可以写这个
matrix we're seeing we could write this
以块矩阵形式减去转置
in block matrix form s minus a transpose
哦，我要把它改成加号
oh I'm going to change that to a plus
因为我更加人还好的一个
because I'm more of a plus person okay a
颠倒
transpose
当我拿走时，是的，是的
and a yeah yeah when I when I took the
导致这打破了我的lambda
derivative this break the lambda I
我没有把减号放在这里
didn't put the minus sign in here and I
我不想让它成为一个加号
didn't want to so let's make it a plus a
再没有什么也没有和
and then there's no nothing there and
X和lambda以及零和
the X and the lambda and the zero and
B是受约束的模型
the B that is the model of a constrained
最小的问题
minimum a minimum problem with
约束它是一个模型，因为
constraints it's a model because the
这里的函数是二次的和
function here is quadratic and the
约束是线性的，你知道
constraints are linear it's a you know
它在六个过程中无处不在
it's in in course six it's everywhere
不断地不断出现
constant constantly appearing as the
最简单的模型好，今天我的观点
simplest model okay and my point today
只是解决方案Xlambda那个
is just that solution X lambda that that
总共解决了X的问题
that total solution the the X together
有一个lambda，这是一个马鞍
with a lambda that that is a saddle
拉格朗日函数的重点是它
point of the lagrangian function l it's
一个马鞍点不是最小的它是那种
a saddle point not a minimum it's sort
在X方向上最小的因为
of a minimum in the X direction because
这是肯定的
this is positive definite that makes
这使得它成为X的函数
that makes that as a function of X it's
上升，但不知何故的外观
going up but somehow the appearance of
lambda使这个矩阵不确定
lambda makes this matrix indefinite it
开始肯定但它有这个
starts positive definite but it has this
转置a和零
a transpose a and that zero
它不可能是大力水手看那个
it couldn't be Popeye look at that
矩阵我看到它不是肯定的
matrix I see it's not positive definite
我怎么看他为什么这么说呢
what do I see him why do I say that
我立刻看着那个矩阵
immediately when I look at that matrix
它不是一个正定矩阵
it's not a positive definite matrix
因为当我看到零时
because when I see that zero on the
对角线肯定是正面的
diagonal that shoots positive definitely
不能采取采取作为示例S
couldn't be take take as an example s
等于31和10取该矩阵
equal three 1 and 1 0 take that matrix
随便闻到我买它2
just random smell I made it to buy 2
而不是大小n加上你知道如何
instead of size n plus in do you see how
我知道那个特征值
do I know that the eigenvalues of that
矩阵一是加号，一个是减号
matrix one is plus and one is minus the
决定因素是否定的，这告诉我
determinant is negative so that tells me
马上，一个是加号，一个是-
right away that one is plus and one is -
谢谢是的，决定因素是消极的
thanks yes yes determinant is negative
不知怎的，这里的决定因素是
and somehow here the determinant is
类似的计算会产生一个
similar calculation would produce a
使用-cuz转置a或某事
transpose a or something with the - cuz
我会这样好，我能我能
I'm going this way well I could I could
做得比这更好，但你看到了
do better than that but you saw the
指出那个简单的矩阵
point that that matrix that simple
这个例子就是特征值
example of this is has eigenvalues are
这两个星座让我快说和
both signs let me just quickly say and
我会把它放在笔记中或那里
I'll put it in the notes or in that
章节我猜这一切都将到来
chapter I guess it all this is coming is
仍然是3.2，原来是4.2
still 3.2 the that was originally 4.2
并且你会看到它，所以我想要什么
and and you'll see it so what do I want
说我想说那个例子
to say I'd like to say that that example
我非常有说服力
is pretty convincing to me that that
如果你说话，这些KKT矩阵
these KKT matrices if if you talk to
人们在优化中是kirusha
people in in optimization that's kirusha
kuhn和tucker三个着名的家伙和
kuhn and tucker three famous guys and
这些是KKT的条件
these are the KKT conditions that that
他们得出了以下拉格罗斯的权利
they derived following lagrosse right
我的意思是，是的，这是一个
and my point is yeah and this is a
典型的排序，所以这是一个不确定的
typical sort so it's it's an indefinite
矩阵我相信如果我这样做的话
matrix I believe it has that one if I do
消除是的告诉我这是一个
elimination yeah tell me this this is a
很好的方式来看待它我想
good way to look at it suppose I do
消除这个或这个
elimination on on this one or on this
一口井假设
one well suppose
我在那里消灭的是第一个
I do elimination there what is the first
枢纽三正，所以现在让我转
pivot three positive so now let me turn
到这里如果我做消除怎么办？
down to here what if I do elimination on
这个块矩阵然后我在这里启动
this block matrix then I start up here
而我和第一个支点是积极的
and I and that first pivot is positive
再一次，这是s是积极的
again right this is s is a positive
确定矩阵不要忘记
definite matrix don't forget
实际上，前n个枢纽都将是
in fact the first n pivots will all be
积极因为第一和枢轴
positive because the first and pivot
搜索你正在努力解决这个问题
search you're working away in this
角落，如果你只是如果你只是
corner and if you only if you're only
想着这个角落的第一个角落
thinking about the first n this corner
是n的大小n然后你甚至没有
is size n by n then you you don't even
看到你正在做一些减法和
see a you're doing some subtractions and
除了枢纽本身，我会做那些
I'll do those but the pivots themselves
来自s的所有人都来了，S是
are coming all coming from s and S is
肯定的，所以我们知道其中一个
positive definite so we know that one of
对正定矩阵的检验
the tests for a positive definite matrix
所有的支点都是积极的，所以我想
is all pivots are positive so I think
所有n个第一支点都将是
all n of the first pivots will be
积极的，当我们使用它们时，让我们
positive and and when we use them let's
刚刚看到，当我们使用它们会发生什么
just see what happens when we use them
[掌声]
[Applause]
所以这就是我开始的KKT矩阵
so so here's the KKT matrix that I start
我最终得到了什么？
with and what do I end up with well
我真正在做的是我在成倍增长
really what I'm doing is I'm multiplying
通过诸如此类的话块行
that block row by something to and
减去杀死我就是这样的
subtracting to kill that a I'm so the
这些排很近，让我放手
these rows well near enough let me let
我做阻止消除块
me do block elimination block
消除就像是容易我没有
elimination is like easier I don't have
写下所有的小数字
to write down all little tiny numbers so
我只想将这一行乘以
I just want to multiply this row by
东西告诉我什么和减去
something tell me what and subtract from
此第二行只是我想有
this second row except I suppose there
我猜他们是数字或字母
are numbers or letters I guess they are
字母我先把它乘以什么
letters what do I multiply that first
逐行减去
row by and subtract
让我们看看这些是不是很小
let's see if these were just little tiny
数字就像3110我是什么
numbers as like in 3 1 1 0 what do I
将该行乘以并减去
multiply that row by and subtract from
这个我乘以一个/s吧
this I multiply by a / s right I do
乘以这使一个AA/S
multiplied by a / s which puts an A
然后我在这里减去所以我会
there then I subtract so here I'll
通过A/S繁殖，但我这些都是
multiply by a / s but I these are
矩阵，所以当我乘以s乘以a
matrices so while I multiply by s by a
SN我乘以倒数
SN I'm multiplying by a s inverse times
我得到了一个，然后我减去了我
this s I get a and then I subtract and I
得到0，当我乘以这个家伙
get to 0 and when I multiply by this guy
减去因为我是减去的我
and subtract I get minus because I'm
减去这个东西-作为逆a
subtracting this thing - a s inverse a
转置是块消除
transpose that was block elimination
换句话说，这只是我
which just in other words it's just I
你已经了解了2个2矩阵
you've learned about 2 by 2 matrices you
现在知道3x加4y等于7和东西
know 3x plus 4y equals 7 and stuff now
我只是用块来做这件事
I'm just doing it with with with blocks
而不是单个数字，但你看
instead of single numbers but you see
这产生了那些积极的支点和
this produced those positive pivots and
你能告诉我关于那个矩阵的什么
what can you tell me about that matrix
什么样的什么可以告诉我
what what kind of what can you tell me
关于标志或特征值或
about the signs or the eigenvalues or
不管这个矩阵是什么意思
whatever of this matrix suppose this was
什么你能告诉我的身份
the identity what could you tell me
关于-aatranspose
about - a a transpose
-aa转换我的声音应该
- a a transpose a my voice should
强调-那就是那个矩阵
emphasize that - it's that matrix there
是负面的，所以虽然
is negative definite so although the
来自的下一组mm枢轴
next set of mm pivots that come from
在这里，我们都会消极，所以我得到了M.
here we'll all be negative so I get M
而nn++n-枢轴
rather n n+ + n- pivots
然后我记得那个枢轴
and and then I remember that the pivots
居然有相同的符号
actually have the same sign as the
特征值，这只是一个美丽的事实
eigenvalues that's just a beautiful fact
我们知道这是肯定的
we know that for for positive definite
那些特征值都是正的
ones the eigenvalues are all positive
枢轴都是积极的，但它是
the pivots are all positive but it's
甚至比这更好的，如果我们有
even better than that that if we have
一些混合物用于枢轴的迹象
some mixture for the signs of the pivots
这告诉我们的迹象
that tells us the signs of the
特征值，这是非常巧妙的事实
eigenvalues that's really neat fact so
我只会写下标志加上和
I'll just write that down signs plus and
减去枢轴的迹象给我们带来了好处
minus signs of pivots give us the plus
或者我伽纳彻减号
or minus signs of the I ganache
所以我潜入了一个漂亮的矩阵
so I've sneaked sneaked in a nice matrix
偏爱对称的定理
theorem that prefer for symmetric
矩阵这是对称矩阵没关系
matrices this is symmetric matrices okay
这就是我想说的约
that's what I wanted to say about
约束和马鞍点即将到来
constraints and saddle points coming
从那里然后我想说
from there and then I want to say
关于约束而不是约束
something about constraints and not
约束现在我要看看
constraints now I'm going to look at the
第二个马鞍点来源
second source of of saddle points so
这些是这个的鞍座
these are the saddles from this
我们所知道的非凡功能
remarkable function that we know so I
现在有一个对称矩阵S可以
now have a symmetric matrix S could be
通常也是肯定的
even positive definite usually it is
你在这里知道R的名字是什么
here do you know what the name for R is
它是一个比例或它命名的商
it's a ratio or a quotient it's named
有人从我们的人开始
after somebody starting with our who's
这真的是一个瑞利
that really right it's a Rayleigh
商
quotient
什么是最大的价值
and what is the largest value possible
我们瑞利商的价值
value of the Rayleigh quotient we've
看到这个想法是最大的价值
seen this idea it is the maximum value
那个比率的瑞利商
of that Rayleigh quotient of that ratio
是lambdamaxrightlambdaone
is is lambda max right lambda one the
最大的一个，退出的是它
biggest one and the exit does it is the
特征向量，因此max是lambda1
eigenvector right so max is is lambda 1
并且在X等于Q，因为Q1转置s
and at X equal Q because Q 1 transpose s
问1Q1转换Q1所以我是
Q 1 over Q 1 transpose Q 1 so I'm
插入这个赢家和Q1是
plugging in this winner and s Q 1 is
lambda1Q1对，这是第一个
lambda 1 Q 1 right it's the first
特征向量，因此lambda1出来了
eigenvector and so a lambda 1 comes out
所以我得到lambda1我知道一切
so I get lambda 1 I know everything
关于那个和我知道的是，如果我把
about that and what I know is if I put
在任何X，我知道如果我放入任何
in any X where do I know if I put in any
X什么，看看这个数字是什么
X whatever and look at this number what
我知道这个数字是否更小
do I know about that number it's smaller
比lambda1或者它可能会击中lambda1
than lambda 1 or it might hit lambda 1
但它并不大，这就是为什么千里马
but it's not bigger that's why Maxima
很容易你放入任何矢量和你
are easy you put in any vector and you
知道你知道发生了什么
know what's happening you know it
不是它不高于最大值
doesn't it's it's not above the max
很明显，什么是min什么的
obviously and what about the min what's
这当然同样简单
that's equally simple of course it's at
底部，所以这将是最小
the bottom so what would be the minimum
如果我是那么真的那个商
of that really of that quotient if I was
寻找
looking for
我将得到什么特征向量和特征值
what eigen vector and eigen value will I
发现当我看到这个，我的底部
find when I look at the bottom of this I
会找到lambda和最后一个人lambda
will find lambda and the last guy lambda
分
min
我认为X将成为它的所在
and the I think where the X will be its
特征向量再次这个东西会
eigenvector and again this stuff will
相等的lambdan，所以我很容易知道
equal lambda n so that's easy I know
如果我放任何矢量无论如何
that if I put in any vector whatever
只需选择n维的任何向量
just choose any vector in n dimensions
并计算X的X现在我也是
and compute R of X what do I now also
知道我们的那个载体
know about our that our of that vector
它比Lambda和下面的更大
it's greater than lambda and below the
最大限度高于男性，但现在如果我投入
max above the men but now if I put in
现在来谈谈其他lambda表达式以及
now what about the other lambdas well
重点是那些是马鞍
the point is that those are saddle
指出这个美丽的东西
points the beautiful thing about this
瑞利商是它的衍生物
Rayleigh quotient is its derivative
在T的鞍点处等于0
equals 0 right at the saddle point at T
在特征向量和它的值
at the eigenvectors and and its value at
特征向量就是特征值
the eigenvectors is the eigenvalue so so
我中有你看到我在说什么，我有
i have you see what i'm saying i have
lambda1这里是最大的lambda，这里是a
lambda 1 here a max lambda and here a
我和他之间有一堆
min and in between i have a bunch of
其他lambdas是马鞍点
other lambdas which are saddle points
如果我把x放入x的2r和
and if i put an x in to the 2 r of x and
看看会发生什么我不知道
look to see what happens i have no idea
我是否在这一侧或下方
whether I'm on this side the below it or
这边是lambda我是马鞍
this side above lambda I so the saddle
积分更难，需要一个
points are more difficult and take a
更多的耐心，所以这是另一个
little more patience so that's the other
马鞍点的来源和我这些
source of saddle points and I so these
是的，让我再强调一下
are so let me just emphasize again what
我在λ等于QKI的lambda说
I'm saying at lambda at X equal Q K I
有一些号码
have some number the
我们的前任有一些积极的
our ex has some number of positive
特征值和一些负数
eigenvalues and some number of negative
适用于QK上下的事情
ones for the things above and below QK
好吧我没时间跟进了
okay I've run out of time to to follow
在那个鞍点上
up on the saddle point part of that on
这张照片的细节我可能会
the details of this picture I might
这将在笔记中，我可能会来
that'll be in the notes and I might come
在下一个开始时回到它
back to it at the very start of next
时间，但我会在此之前你会
time but I will before that you will
有三个实验室然后我
have the lab number three and then I
我认为我们应该讨论它，因为我
think we should discuss it because I
没有完成这个实验室，这是它的意图
haven't done this lab it's it's intended
给你一些过度拟合的感觉
to give you some feeling for overfitting
并且还打算给你一点
and also intended to give you a little
介绍深度学习等
introduction to deep learning and so
我会告诉你的，我们可以谈谈
I'll get it to you and we can talk about
星期三，它将不会到期
it Wednesday and again it won't be due
until the Wednesday after break okay
到休息后的星期三好吧
谢谢，我星期三见
thanks so I'll see you Wednesday